[Music]
this program is brought to you by
Stanford University please visit us at
stanford.edu
the last time I told you that proper
time is defined by D to^ 2 is equal to
dx^ 2 or sorry the t^2 minus the x^2
and the question was where does the
minus sign come
from well the whole the whole point of
the Lorent Transformations the whole
point of it is that they conserve or
preserve uh quantities like the T ^2
minus the x^2 they don't preserve
quantities like the t s plus the x
s uh
if we make a lorence transformation to a
new set of coordinates X Prime and T
Prime then not
only is x^2 or let's let's say t^2 -
x^2 equal to T Prime 2 - x Prime
s but if we take any little differential
displacement DX
DT that it's also true of the
differential displacements that they are
also conserved or that this quantity the
corresponding quantity DT ^2 minus dx^ s
is invariant under Lorent
Transformations now we want the idea of
proper time or distance along a
trajectory to be Lorenson variant we
want it to be the
same in fact that's what we mean by it
we mean something that has physically
measurable meaning physic measurable
meaning means among other things that it
doesn't depend on the coordinate
frame the quantity DT ^2 + dx^ 2 would
vary from reference frame to reference
frame if you take the Loren
Transformations and you work out how x
and t transform you'll find out that
things like T ^2 + x^2 or DT ^2 plus
dx2 change when you vary from one frame
to another and so they're not good good
candidates for invariant measurable
well-defined observable quantities they
vary from frame to
frame uh it's the quantity DT ^2 minus
DX s which is the
invariant all right let's uh let's
start I see I got something to eat thank
goodness I was about to faint
um just give me a second to find my
place ah
good first
announcement I've been getting a lot of
emails from a lot of people not just in
this class but from all over the place
uh who watch these lectures and send a
lot of email asking good and interesting
questions the problem for me is that
there's too many of them but on the
other hand very many of them are very
very
similar uh I try to answer them and I do
answer them for the most part but I
decided there's a more efficient
strategy for dealing with this uh since
so many of the questions are very
similar what I decided to do is to start
a blog the purpose of this blog
incidentally is by is not to discuss
pical uh
political controversy I have no interest
whatever in doing that I have interest
in nothing but answering physics
questions uh some fraction of which
probably most of them would come from
not this class so much but from this
class in the extended sense of the
people who also watch it on the
internet uh so I DEC decided to try and
open a Blog which I managed to do today
just because I got a whole bunch of
questions which were similar and so I'm
going to ask you instead of sending
questions to my email directly send them
to the blog and I'll give you the
address of the
blog I never had a Blog before in fact I
never wanted a Blog
before but I realized it might serve
some purpose
as long as I manage to control myself
and keep my polemical uh side suppressed
which I will do and and so should
anybody who is sending mail to me or to
to the blog forget pmics I won't answer
it
forget whether string theory is not even
wrong or just plain wrong or whether I
personally am the trouble with physics
or whatever forget that stuff if you
have for example if you have a question
like why was the sign in such and such
an equation on the Blackboard plus and
not minus I think you made a mistake
I'll be glad to answer that uh I'll also
be glad to answer any questions which
are real questions which I know the
answer
to uh outside the context of this
class and perhaps if I don't know the
answer somebody else does know the
answer so it can serve some good purpose
but as I said I will not address uh
pical questions anyway the uh the blog
address for those who want to use it
is I suppose they're all lowercase but I
have this habit of writing uh uppercase
suin
blog physics it's all one
word
for everyone
now I can do
blog
spot.com no no no there was a purpose to
making it very
long the purpose is you have to really
want the
answer nobody's going to come to this
who isn't looking for an answer to a
specific
question uh hm
yeah susin blog physics for everyone.
blogspot.com and let's use that I rather
use that than the usual class for class
purposes
when will uh when will there be a class
will there be a class this uh Sunday at
midnight or whatever use the class
thing but if you have a question a real
question about physics and it doesn't
have to be about details of the class if
you have a question about physics let's
post them on
this and that way uh I don't wind up
answering the same question endless
numbers of times which I really don't
mind but it got to be a little bit
much okay so now let's uh get to field
Theory before I go back to relativity
and we will go back to relativity
because we're not quite finished with it
but um this class is both about
relativity and field Theory so I'd like
to get started a little bit on
discussing what field theory
is now we're talking about classical
field Theory this quarter I might here
and there mention a bit about Quantum
field Theory just a very little bit put
some of the ideas together with a bit of
quantum
mechanics but it's primarily about
classical field Theory so what does
classical mean
classical does not mean that it comes
from ancient Greece it means that it
doesn't involve quantum mechanics as you
know so classical field theory is the
theory of classical Fields what are
Fields fields are things which fill
space and time electric Fields magnetic
fields gravitational fields their
conditions in SpaceTime which determine
all kinds of things yes that's exclude
relativity no as a rule uh the question
was does classical exclude relativity no
the it's almost a technical term when
one speaks about classical one strictly
means excluding quantum mechanics uh for
example one speaks about classical
general relativity versus quantum
General Rel versus quantum gravity
classical Gravity versus quantum gravity
and so no uh one does not ex one does
ex which way is
it classical means non-quantum
mechanical and that's all what does
semi what does semi classical
mean when we I'll tell you when we get
to
it it's a good
question uh but let's talk about what
field Theory means Fields mean Electric
magnetic gravitational fields other
fields which also occur in physics uh
there are a lot of them not just the
usual standard ones that uh that you
learn about uh in elementary physics
there the higs
field uh there's the Yang Mills Fields
there's the inflaton field whole bunches
of them and physics uh makes very clear
that those things exist but what they
are is they're fields in SpaceTime that
vary from place to place from time to
time and that need equations to govern
how they uh how they evolve with with
time all right now field Theory
classical field theory is a combination
of two basic disciplines one of them is
special
relativity of course you can have field
Theory which is not relativistic it's
perfectly thinkable but uh to have to
have a field Theory which does not
satisfy Fields just mean things which f
space you can have field theories which
don't satisfy the rules of uh of
Relativity I'm saying what I mean by
saying you can have them is you can
imagine writing down equations for
fields which don't satisfy the
principles of special relativity but
that's not what this class is about this
class is about relativistic field Theory
so it's a combination of the special
theory of
relativity and classical
mechanics it's classical mechanics
applied to the theory of
fields so I want to begin by reviewing
the principles of classical mechanics
was that last quarter I can't remember I
lose track of The
Quarters Fall quarter what what do we do
last last quarter we did quantum
mechanics thank you all right um let's
review a little bit about classical
mechanics one of the ways of summarizing
the principles of of classical mechanics
are through the principle of least
action so let's go back to the principle
of least
action we describe a system by a system
of
coordinates the
coordinates the typical situation that
we used to that we're familiar with is
where the coordinates are coordinates
describing the location of
particles they don't have to be they
could be any set of coordinates
describing a physical system in
particular they could be the values of
fields at different places in space but
we'll come to that whatever those
coordinates are that describe the state
of a system the configuration of a
system we combine them together and we
call them the set of variables
Q now in the simple situations that
we're familiar with there typically are
several Q's more than one of them the
q's could stand for the positions of
particles if there are n
particles moving on a line all the
particles moving on the same line then
there are n coordinates and we might
call them
X I don't want to call them X now and
the reason I'm calling them Q is because
X is going to have some other
significance for us but
uh some number of coordinates Q it could
be a single particle moving in three
dimensions then there are three Q's in
fact there would be three Q's X Y and Z
for a particle moving in three
dimensions there would be three Q's if
there were three particles all moving in
one dimension so the fact that there are
three q's and not s Q's or 14 Q's or 10
Q's doesn't necessarily tell you how
many dimensional problem you're working
in but it does tell you how many
coordinates it takes to describe a
system so we could label mq sub I where
I runs from one to anything we could
even imagine systems of infinitely many
particles uh we might get a little bit
confused then about uh labeling them but
still we can imagine systems with
infinitely many particles filling all of
space from uh from one end of space to
the other end of space but let's uh
stick with for the moment with finitely
many of them and the other thing we need
to know in order to get
started with a system and to predict its
future is the velocities which means the
time derivatives or the rate of change
of the q's with respect to time Q subi
dot time derivative so Q subis are
typically functions of time as are the
time derivatives and one the time
derivatives are just gotten by
differentiating with respect the
time all right the laws of physics and
as far as we know all of the laws of
physics that we know all the basic laws
of
physics uh Newton's Laws electromagnet
electromagnetic Theory Einstein's Law
Einstein and Newton's laws of gravity
the theory of the higs particle uh
everything that we know about can be
derived from the principle of least
action the principle of least action
begins well first of all it begins with
a picture
as always we draw the time axis
upward in the horizontal Direction the
horizontal Direction stands let's let's
put a couple of horizontal directions in
but the horizontal directions really
stand for all the possible cues of a
system so the horizontal directions
don't have to be three-dimensional space
they could be 300,000 dimensional space
if there were 300,000 particles moving
on a line it simply rep presents the
various coordinates q1 Q2 Q3 and so
forth and specifying a set of Q's at the
beginning for example means starting at
a
point on the space of Q's all right
so an initial condition corresponds to a
set of Q's which is a point in the space
and the set of Q dots the set of Q Dot
dots tells you the way the point is
moving at initial time equals Zer so it
gives you some idea of the direction
that the various qes are moving off
in that's the starting point system
described by q's and Q dots the
principle of least action says that you
can determine not that you can but the
trajectory of all
systems the trajectory means its history
its history starting with some initial
configuration and ending with some final
configuration incidentally the word
configuration refers to the cues it's a
technical term it means the values of a
set of cu's it does not mean a set of Q
dots so when one speaks about a
configuration it means for example
fixing the location of all the particles
without fixing their velocity so that
that word configuration keep in
mind uh we might ask given that a system
starts at one
configuration and ends after a Time T at
another configuration exactly how does
it move in
between what's the path that it takes
through the configuration space how does
it move with time and the answer is
every known
system satisfies the principle of least
action
which means that there's an expression
called the
action which is built up out of the Q
dots and the q's which is minimized
which achieves the minimum value that it
can take on along the
trajectory physically allowable
trajectories are Minima of the action
now what is the action the action always
has the form of an integral over time DT
of something that's called a
lran the lran is something that's made
out of the q's and the Q
dots so it's some
lran which depends on Q and Q
Dot and one speaks about the action
between the initial and final
configuration so that means the integral
is from some initial time T1 to some
final time T2
and the trajectories that we explore the
trajectories that we're going to
explore the different trajectories that
we're going to compare to find the one
of least action are all trajectories
which pass through the same two
points so we specify a problem by
specifying an initial and a final
configuration and asking which of the
many trajectories will minimize the
action all right now what is this thing
called the lran as I said the lran is
just a function of the coordinates and
the velocities and it typically has not
always not
always but it typically has a simple
form consisting of
a kinetic energy
T which depends on the Q dots and I'll
write down an example in a moment minus
a potential
energy the potential energy only depends
on the q's it does not depend on the Q
dots at all it depends on position but
not
velocity the kinetic energy sometimes
depends on both the simplest systems
that we can think about particles moving
and so forth the kinetic energy as a
rule depends only on the
velocities and so for example if Q
actually represented if the q's
represented points moving on a line
let's imagine points moving on a line
whole bunch of
them some are moving this way some are
moving that way and so
forth then the q's would simply stand
for the positions of the points along
the line their velocities would be the Q
dots and their kinetic energy would be
1/2 the mass of the I particle times the
square of its velocity so we would write
that t is is equal to 1/2 a sum over all
the
particles sum of
I particles labeled according to
I 12 the mass of the I particle time Q
sub I do
squared and then we would have minus the
potential
energy minus U of Q and this U of Q
would in general depend on all of the
positions of the particles it would not
itself be a sum over individual
particles in general for example there
might be forces between Pairs of
particles in that case the use might
come from a sum over pairs of particles
but in general it's just a potential
energy which depends on the positions of
all the
particles this is a simple example
coming from the mechanics of particles
more generally
T could I'm sorry I've written something
so here T minus U is equal to
this T minus U
okay um keep in mind one thing the lran
is not the energy the energy is the
kinetic energy plus the potential energy
okay so that was that's the basic
structure of classical
mechanics
pick a pair of points one we can think
of as an initial and the other a final
starting point and ending point two
points in the configuration space
separated by a total amount of time call
it t compute the action the integral of
the lran from the beginning of the
trajectory to the end of the trajectory
clearly depends on the trajectory
because the q's and the Q dotts depend
on the trajectory and then explore
around and look for the trajectory which
minimizes the action that will be the
solution to your
problem okay that's the principle of
least action without
it we would have no concept of energy
momentum and so forth and I refer you
back to the uh uh the previous uh the
previous pre the previous to the
previous lecture series on classical
Mechanics for the details but um there's
one detail which is
important the detail which is important
is one might get the feeling from this
that there's something teic about
physics theological what is the word te
theological can somebody Define
theological for me I know what it means
but I can't Define it toward a goal
pointed toward a goal or somehow
mysteriously um uh
knows about the uh the end point as well
as the beginning There's Something About
This which seems a little bit too
theological whereas we know that the
properties of physical
trajectories are things which can be
determined from local differential
equations that the behavior of a
trajectory can also be described not by
This Global I call it Global because
that involves a whole trajectory not by
global uh constraints like the principle
of least action but this Newton's
equations f equals ma which tells you
what the trajectory does at each little
increment along the trajectory and so
there's some other description which is
local local along the trajectory
differential equations that means what's
the connection between the two of them
well the connection is actually very
simple supposing I take a
trajectory which I
am suspecting is the solution of my
problem and now supposing I vary it a
little bit just vary it a little bit
along the
trajectory then I will necessarily
increase the action so if I knew that
the action was minimum for every little
displacement that I could make of the
trajectory that would be the same as
knowing that the action was minimum for
the whole trajectory so if I know the
trajectory gets to here and I know it
gets to here then I can ask a perfectly
local question or at least a small
question let's call it a small question
instead of a big question I can require
that the trajectory has the least action
between these two
points and that's that's a condition
which really only depends on what's
going on in the neighborhood of those
two nearby points if we bring those
points very close together
the condition for minimizing the action
over that small region there becomes a
differential equation it becomes the
oiler lrange equations of motion which I
won't derive but that's exactly where
they come from from requiring that the
action be minimized with respect to a
small little deviation of the
trajectory and those equations are
differential equations I'll write them
down we've studied them before but uh
we're just reviewing
now the oila lrange equations are simply
for each there's a separate equation for
each one of the coordinates Q
subi so if there are 100,000 coordinates
then there are 100,000 equations as
there should be because there should be
a separate equation for each
coordinate if we're going to determine
all of the coordinates and the way they
move there better be a lot of
equations basically f equals ma for each
particle in the system system for each
component of motion of each
particle the equation for the I
coordinate is you first construct the
derivative of the
lran with respect to the velocity
associated with that coordinate the
derivative of the lran with respect to
qabi dot all right so let's see let's
read this off that would be in this case
partial of L with respect to Qi Dot
I here could stand for seven seven or 14
or 23 or however we label of particles
pick one partial of L with respect to Q
subi dot that's just equal to m q subi
dot this quantity is also known as the
canonical momentum conjugate to the
coordinate q and it's often written P
ofi the canonical momentum and notice
that it is the momentum masstimes
velocity uh for the usual particle on a
line p is M subi
qabi it's
this we differentiate that with respect
to time along the
trajectory along the trajectory we
differentiate that with respect to
time minus the derivative of the lran
with respect to q
subi and and that's equal to zero for
each one of the coordinates these are
the oil lrange equations and they're
equivalent to Newton
equations Newton's equations one for
each particle let's check that let's see
let's work that
out the derivative of the L grangian
with respect to Q subi that's m q subi
dot we have to differentiate that once
more so this term here becomes
M which we always assume that the masses
of particles are constant they don't
vary so that's M times qabi double
dot an extra derivative here is
this and that's of course Mass h m m
subi thank
you m sub i q subi double do what is
that that's mass times acceleration of
the I particle for example as an
example uh and that is equal to let's
put this on the right hand side DL by DQ
subi all right now where are the Q
subis in this expression for this simple
L grangian here which has the form of a
function of velocities plus a function
of positions typical
situation uh the only places that the
q's themselves appear is in the
potential energy so this gives us just
then
minus the derivative of potential energy
with respect to Q
subi This of course is just the force on
the E particle the gradient of the
potential energy with respect to
position or minus it to be more precise
is the force on the E
particle
uh for our purposes we'll just Define
this to be the force notice it depends
on position it does not depend on
velocity now there are Velocity
dependent forces in nature and we'll
come to them they tend to happen when
there's mixed q and Q dot dependence in
lran here they all velocity anybody
knows any examples of some velocity
dependent
forces yeah the magnetic force on a not
on a magnetic uh not on a magnet but on
a on a Charged particle on an electric
qu charged
particle uh the faster it moves the
larger the force on it
so this is not the most general form of
lran that you can write down
but this rule principle of least action
is the most general form that we know of
for the laws of physics okay so there we
are f equals ma F on the right hand side
Ma on the right on the left hand side
and that's a typical example
[Applause]
what is field
Theory field theory is a theory in which
the degrees of freedom are fields which
fill space they also vary with time but
for the moment let's concentrate on the
way they fill
space The
Q's The Q's are the values of fields at
different positions in
Space the reason I didn't want to call
the coordinates of a
particle X is I wanted to reserve X for
another qu well just for position
abstract position not necessarily the
position of a particle not necessarily
the coordinate that will go in the lran
but just a position in space that
position in space might not be the
position of a particle it might just be
a position in space
in a field Theory a position of space
labels the labels the location of a
degree of Freedom it is not itself a
degree of freedom but it labels a degree
of Freedom so for example let's you know
what I you know what I think I'll do I
think what I will do is work out an
example of a field Theory from the
beginning showing you how it comes about
from this from a simple from a simple
mechanical system which when you take a
certain limit becomes a field Theory I
think it will do more to explain the
idea than uh than to describe it
abstractly the system is a collection of
Springs a collection of Springs
connected together to form a string not
a string of super String Theory but a
violin string or something like a violin
string something Slinky is even a better
example but here's the system that I
want to begin
with it is in fact a violin string or a
guitar string a string connecting two
points uh what do you call a thing that
holds the string the ends of the string
the post in a in a violin I forget
uh one end is a bridge the other end is
a the the the thing you
turn the
hook egg Peg Peg ah okay yeah so from
the bridge to the peg but we don't have
to distinguish which end is the bridge
and which end is the
peg we have a string stretched
out whoops I missed the peg there it
is all right now I'm going to make a
simplifying assumption about the
string the strings the points of the
string don't move horizontally they move
only vertically that's a simplifying
assumption but it's a pretty good
assumption it's much easier if you think
about it for a minute it's much easier
to get the string vibrating vertically
than it is to get it vibrating
horizontally it uh typically is the
string is much stiffer to to get it
moving horizontally than it is
vertically so let's uh let's
Let's ignore the horizontal motions of
the points of the string and only
concentrate on the vertical motion now
to get a handle on it let's begin by
imagining that instead of a string we
have a collection of Springs and a
collection of Springs means a collection
of mass points
which move
vertically but have Springs I'll draw
The Springs in a different
color have Springs connecting
them in the limit that we take a
continuously infinite collection of mass
points in the limit that we take that
continuous
limit this string becomes a field or a
mathematical model for a field it's not
a field in real space but it has the
mathematical structure of a field in a
space that exists between the post and
the the um the Peg and the uh the other
end whatever it's
called okay in other words we can define
a
variable it's really just the
height of the mass Point incidentally
there's nothing to prevent Mass points
from going lower here
also we could call it y but I'm not
going to call it y I'm going to call the
height of the I point I'm going to label
it fi whoops f
subi f subi is simply the displacement
in the vertical direction of the I Mass
point and I want to study the equations
for this thing we can get a pretty good
idea we know what's going to happen
waves are going to go up and down when
we take the limit it's going to form a
uh um a mathematical string the string
is going to have waves that can
propagate up and down there'll be waves
of different frequency different
wavelength and so forth we have a pretty
good idea what's going to happen but we
want to describe this using the laws of
mechanics and using in particular the
principle of least action or more
specific spefically the oila lrange
equations which follow from the
principle of least action all right so
let's see if we can write down an action
for this literally thinking of it as a
collection of mass points and um and
springs now let's assume that the
separation let's call the horizontal
axis the
x-axis notice that X labels a point but
it is not itself a coordinate of the
system the FI are the coordinates the
things which are the
q's are the FI they represent the
dynamical degrees of freedom they
represent what you need to know in order
to get started the X's the X just labels
which one you're talking about this is x
equals whatever this is x equals twice
whatever three times whatever and
let's assume that the distance between
neighboring
points along the x- axis let's call that
Epsilon at the end of the day we're
going to add more and more and more mass
points and Shrink Epsilon to zero in
such a way that they continue to stretch
between xals 0 and x equals whatever the
end point is
here so as we add more and more mass
points will shrink the Gap now first
question what should we take to be the m
mass of the I point supposing we took
the mass to be a gram or or a kilogram
or whatever as we add more and more mass
points and fill up the gaps with more
and more mass points it's pretty clear
that the mass of that string is going to
become infinite as we add more and more
mass points if the mass per particle is
fixed what we're going to want to do is
imagine that a segment of string has a
overall Mass which doesn't change as you
add more and more points to do that
we're going to have to shrink the mass
of the uh of mass points as we add more
particles in particular we'll have to
assume that the mass of the I
particle is proportional to Epsilon
let's just call it
Epsilon the distance as Epsilon shrink
smaller and smaller and we crowd more
and more mass points in there will
shrink the masses so that the net Mass
between two points on the x-axis here
stays
fixed so that means the mass of the I
point is proportional to Epsilon as it
shrinks and let's just take it all the
mass points to be the same mass of size
Epsilon and let's write down the kinetic
energy now the kinetic energy is the
energy of motion along the F AIS which
means the vertical a
here what is
it the kinetic energy is
12 the mass of the I particle well first
of all we're going to have to sum we'll
we'll eventually
sum summation over all the particles the
mass of the I particle which is
Epsilon and then the square of of
velocity which is after all just 5 do s
f subi do s divided by two 12 mass time
the velocity
squared that Epsilon is in a rather
convenient place for later purposes let
me tell you what the later purposes
are later on we're going to replace this
sum by an
integral when we start filling this up
with more and more dense points the sum
is going to turn into an integral that's
obvious let me just remind you of the
relation between sums and
integrals if we have a
function on an axis and the interval
between neighboring
points is well whatever that interval is
let's call it Delta
X then the definition of an
integral F
DX is just a
summation over all the values of the
functions at all these discrete points
summation of I of the value of the
function at the I point call it x sub I
time Delta
X that's what this DX is there that DX
really means Delta
X and of course f ofx * Delta of X is
just the area under
that height f with
Delta I have a question yeah um when you
say that uh
X
labels um the the points yeah uh would
that be something
like
um x = uh x0 + I
Epsilon in other words I I know what
you're asking I know what you're asking
the X's of course up at this
point are discret
all right there's not a particle at
every X there's a particle at a discrete
collection of X of of x's the allowable
X's that correspond to particles are
separated by an interval Epsilon I think
that's roughly what you're asking well I
is already an index and X is yeah yeah
there's a redundant that's right there's
a redundancy of the of U of notations
here I could choose to label the
particle by I or I could choose to label
it by
xabi the reason I have the redundancy is
to is to um reinforce in your mind first
of all that we're just talking about
different particles that's the I index
but later on we're going to take a
limit where the identity the discrete
identity of the particle is going to be
replaced by a continuous identity of
degrees of freedom labeled by X it will
no longer be a good idea to label them
by I we'll label them by X but X X at
this point x and xub are sort of
redundant
descriptions of the name of the particle
all right the label for the particle
good all right now the connection though
between integrals and sums is of course
integral f ofx is the limit i' I've
suppressed the limit but you know of
course that there's a limit in which
Delta f x goes to zero which Delta of X
goes to zero Delta X in this example is
just
Epsilon so an integral is a
sum multiplied by
Epsilon well here we have a sum
multiplied by
Epsilon it's not too hard I'm I'm not
going to use this yet but I just want to
point out what this Epsilon is doing
here it's quite obvious that this is
eventually going to be replaced by the
integral
DX of 12
F do^
2ar the Epsilon will become the DX
that's what happens to Epsilon F do SAR
well F will instead of being a function
of a discrete index will become a
function of
X and the sum will become an
integral so it's good to have this
Epsilon there it's in just the right
place to replace this infinite sum
by uh an ordinary integral I'm not going
to use that yet we're going to come back
to
that now what about the potential
energy the potential
energy the potential energy of a
spring is proportional to the square of
the displacement of the spring from its
equilibrium
position now each one of these
Springs just think of it uh that the
equilibrium position of the Springs the
Springs only respond to Vertical motion
Let's Pretend the Springs only uh
respond to Vertical
motion and they tend to pull neighboring
particles
together there's no direct interaction
between particle number 13 over here and
156 over here the only interaction is
through the intervening particles the
direct interaction is between the
neighboring particles when you separate
at the neighboring particles vertically
the spring gets
stretched the stretching of the spring
is proportional to the difference f i
let's say f i + 1 minus 5 I that's how
much the spring between I and I + one
are is stretched so for example this
might be the I particle this might be
the I + first
I + 1 could be seven I could be six
right this is how
much
the spring connecting I and I +1 is
stretched if I and i+ one are at the
same height that spring is not stretched
it's when they're pulled apart that it's
stretched so that's how much it's
stretched and the potential energy of a
stretched spring is proportional
to the
square of the of the distance that it's
stretched so that means we should expect
the potential energy in that spring to
be proportional to the
difference of the two coordinates
squared we need a coefficient the spring
constant in front of it the usual
formula is to put a spring constant
divided by
two that would be the potential energy
of a single spring
we're going to take and you'll see
why incidentally um all right let me let
me explain
why supposing you have a
spring it's made of iron or whatever a
good spring is made out of it could be a
rubber band anything that that forms
like a spring and it has a certain
spring constant K it represents the
stiffness of the spring right it's hooks
law
uh spring constant K supposing you cut
the spring in half this way so that it's
only half a
spring and throw the other half away
what happens to the spring constant of
the half spring is it bigger than or
less than the spring constant of the
original
spring I hear every possible answer and
then
some it's bigger the spr it's stiffer
if you cut a spring in half it's stiffer
it's hard harder to stretch it a
centimeter a tiny tiny spring is much
harder to stretch a centimeter than a
long than a than a long spring so the
spring constant if we took this spring
and replaced it by two
Springs each one of those Springs would
have twice the spring constant that
means the the spring constant has the
Epsilon in the denominator the smaller
Epsilon the bigger the spring
constant all right with that and we'll
see that that works out just right to
convert the differences to derivatives
integrals summations to integrals but
that's the physical reason why the
smaller the spring is the larger the
spring constant which means we ought to
put the Epsilon in the denominator not
in the
numerator okay let's do that let's put
an Epsilon in the denominator and then
there's a possible coefficient the
possible numerical number that goes in
the numerator it might distinguish
different kinds of materials it might
distinguish how tightly the uh the the
string is stretched just some numerical
coefficient there that actually carries
some Dimensions with it and I'm going to
give it a name I'm going to call it c
squared
I call it c^
s um for reasons that will become
clear
okay this is the potential energy of a
single spring but now we should add them
all
up all the pairs all the neighboring
pairs add them all up to find the total
potential energy right so the potential
energy is the sum over neighboring
pairs
of 5 I + 1 - 5 i^
2ar c^
2 divided by
two let's uh make some room here U is
equal to c^2 over 2 Epsilon
the
difference of F at neighboring points
squared summed over all the neighboring
pairs well now we have everything we
need to write down the equations of
motion of this system we have t we have
U we can write down the
lran and once we have the lran we can
apply the oiler lrange equations to each
one of the separate uh fi
coordinates okay so the L grangian
then there's a summation over
I Epsilon / 2 I can take the Epsilon
over2 on the outside Let's Take It
Outside Epsilon over
2 summation over I F subi do^
2ar and then another term minus U
remember you subtract the uh the um
potential
energy
minus summation well let's minus c^2
over 2
Epsilon summation now you know what I'm
going to call this I'm just going to
call it Delta F squared Delta f means
the difference between pi on two
neighboring
sites Delta
fi
squared but it does mean
fius 5 I + 1 2
I uh yeah it's Delta 5 I squ yeah I'm
not sure the qu the only reason I didn't
write it is because should we call it
Delta fi or Delta fi + one but you know
what I mean it's just saving me uh it
means this it means this and you sum up
all the
contributions okay let's now take
that before we take the
limit uh let's uh work out the equations
of
motion and then take the limit in which
the number of Springs becomes
continuously
infinite uh all right let's put this up
on the
top well the potential energy is clearly
positive because it corresponds to a
hooks law where you have to do work to
stretch the spring so the potential
energy is positive you could imagine a
system with the opposite Behavior but it
would have very bad properties uh it
would be unstable but let's uh let's
just
let's it's a good question let me come
back to it when we have a uh when it
doesn't interrupt the flow of
um uh of the
thought yeah the the question was where
do we get the sign of this from we get
the sign from T minus U but why but that
but that simply replaces it with the
question why is the potential energy
positive the potential energy is
positive because you have to do work to
stretch the spring
okay that of course there's an
assumption about Springs you can imagine
crazy Springs uh where when you pull
them apart they tend to push you even
more
apart and it's actually the condition
that the spring has a restoring Force
instead of an anti- restoring
Force good okay so now let's work out
allrange equations of
motion let's go to the I whenever I do
this I get completely confused by all
these indices the indices drive me crazy
and what I have to do is I have to work
it out for I equal 7 once I've worked it
out for I equals 7 I see the pattern and
I can work it out for any I so let's
focus on it doesn't have to be seven but
uh let's focus on I equals 7 we're going
to work out the equation of motion for f
sub 7 or f of x sub 7 5 sub7 all right
where does 57 occur and where does 5.7
occur 5.7 occurs in only one term
here so the
derivative partial of
L with respect to 5
do
7 is just equal to Epsilon * 5.7
right did I get it
right yeah okay now once I do that then
I look at it and I say oh oh oh oh I I I
got the pattern now 5 I
dot is Epsilon 5 sub
actually by now I've done this enough
times that I don't really have to plug
in seven but when it comes to this term
over here this one is confusing enough
that I have to focus think seven think
seven all right so let's now calculate
well this is sorry let's now
differentiate it d by
DT that's this all right so that's the
left hand side or the first term in the
oila lrange equation for f sub
I all right now let's focus on the
potential term we have to compute for
the right hand side minus du by we have
to compute the right hand side that's
equal to
minus
duu
by
D7 57 enters into two of these and only
two only two terms here contain 57 the
one that involves a spring between six
and seven and the one that involves a
spring between seven and 8 none of the
other Springs involve 57 so there's
going to be two
terms all right let's just work out what
they are the two terms involving
57 so U that particular term is c^2 over
T Epsilon
on 5 8 - 5 7^ 2ar which incidentally is
the same as 57 - 58
SAR okay doesn't matter which order we
write it 57 - 58 squared is the same as
58 - 5 7^ 2 and then
plus c^ 2 over 2
Epsilon 5
6 - 5
squared and again it doesn't matter
whether we write 57 - 56 so 56 - 7
they're the same thing
squared okay now we have to write here
du by
D7 the U by
d57 first of all contains c^
2 A minus sign from the defining minus
sign over here and now c^2 over 2
c^2 over 2 Epsilon times the derivative
of this thing here with respect to 57
what's the derivative of this with
respect to
57 well it's twice 57us 58 is that right
yeah
uh H say it
again uh 58 - 57
yeah well wait a minute it doesn't
matter whether we write 57 minus 5 let's
see
um I think it's 57 minus
yeah 57us 58 right so it's 57us
58 no
two the two from down here cancel the
two when I differentiated H you have it
oh I have it there I I should have
erased it good thank
you now there's the term which is
entirely identical except instead of
eight we have six no difference other
than the substitution of six versus 8
and so there's another term which is
plus 57
Min -
56 all let's see if we can see what the
pattern is let me write the general
pattern the general pattern now is
Epsilon f i dble dot is equal looks like
minus I think I got the minus right c^2
over
Epsilon c^2 over Epsilon
twice f
i well let's write let's let's write f
i - 5 I + 1 + 5 i - 5
ius1 so basically what's happening is
the seventh spring is being pulled by
both the eighth and the sixth spring
okay and each one of these disappears
there now let me write this in a
slightly different form let me write
this as F well let's write it as um yeah
let's change the sign here let's change
the overall sign put a minus here A Plus
here A minus here and a plus here okay
all I did was take the minus sign and
bring it on the inside of the
parentheses here now here we have
58 minus
57 what do you think's going to happen
to this 58 minus 57 when we try to take
a limit in which the uh in which it
becomes
continuous what happens to D the
differences when you uh shrink the gap
between
things well indeed they go to zero but
before they go to
zero just before they go to zero they're
proportional to the derivative
PI right differences become
derivatives we'll keep that in mind uh
in particular notice there's an Epsilon
in the denominator there so it looks
like we're going to get some kind of
derivative now then there's
minus and let me put in
parentheses
minus
5 7 minus 56
so I have 58 - 57 minus 57 -
56 any idea what this whole thing will
become the second derivative it's the
difference of the differences the
difference between 8 and seven
less seven and six this is going to
become a second
derivative all right but before we do
that let's divide by this Epsilon
here and
then well let's let's not divide let's
just write down the equation of
motion
uh Epsilon F sub I double dot I'm now
letting
7bi is equal to c^2 over Epsilon
times 5 I + 1 - 5 I that's this
one
minus 5 i - 5 i - one
now this is an awkward looking thing but
when we fiddle around with it we'll see
that this is a very simple wave equation
very simple wave equation let's divide
by Epsilon on both sides first then we
get Epsilon squared
downstairs all right now let's take one
of these
epsilons and group it right here
I've used up one of the epsilons
here by bringing it inside the
bracket what is this going to be this in
the limit in which Epsilon goes to zero
is going to be the derivative of
f with respect to X
but evaluated at a point midway between
I and I +
1 we can think of it that way it's sort
of symmetric between I and I + 1 you can
think of it as the derivative of f with
respect to X evaluated halfway between I
and I + 1 what about this one
here that's
minus the derivative Let's uh let's well
let's
minus the derivative of f with respect
to X but not at the same point at a
point which is
shifted one less all right so if this is
halfway between seven and 8 or halfway
between 8 and seven then this one is
halfway between seven and
six so this is the difference of
derivatives it's the difference of
derivatives evaluated at two points
separated by distance
Epsilon you can think of it as the
difference of D DX when you move a step
Epsilon but what happens when I divide
that by one/
Epsilon what happens to it what's it
become the second derivative this just
becomes in the limit that Epsilon goes
to zero becomes the second derivative of
f with respect to Epsilon squar
now notice that none of this would have
worked out very nicely had I not put the
epsilons in in the right place to begin
with for example had I made the mistake
of thinking uh that the spring
constant x squ x
squ thank
you second partial ofy with respect to x
squared had I put the epsilons in in the
wrong places they would have showed up
in the fin final equation in some form
which would not have allowed me to take
a limit so here we are Here's the final
equation F oh what happened to C squ we
left it we left out c
s c^
s i double
dot or let's write it second partial of
f with respect to time squared
is equal to
c^2 * 2 partial of Pi with respect to x
s or even better well I don't know
better or different let's write it this
way I like to write things uh which are
equal to
zero second derivative of five with
respect to time
minus c^ 2 * the second derivative of 5
with respect to x^2 is equal to
Z all right now that's a nice equation
now because Epsilon has disappeared out
of it of course Epsilon is still there
but the point is we've made some
approximations where we approximated
discrete differences by derivatives
those approximations become good
approximations become exact in the limit
that Epsilon goes goes to zero so we
don't even really have to do anything to
get the limit in which Epsilon goes to
zero Epsilon doesn't even appear in the
equation anymore now as I said I
emphasize it doesn't appear in the
equations because we made some
approximations that Epsilon was very
small the real point is that the limit
Epsilon goes to zero is a nice smooth
limit where Epsilon drops out of the
equations and the equation for f just
becomes comes a simple wave equation for
waves which propagate up and down the
x-axis with what
velocity
c h did I get it wrong wait hold
on uh let's just check the dimensions of
C I might I've done this more than once
wrong Let's uh let's check
Dimensions okay
so
uh apart from the dimension of I which I
don't care about since it appears in
both of these here I have a dimension 1/
time
squared much much equal a thing with
Dimension c^2 over
x^2 all right so it appears then that
whatever C is it has dimensions of X
over
T I think that's velocity isn't
it I think I got it right yeah you did I
did yeah so C is the velocity of
propagation of
the uh waves up and down this
string excuse me a
second hello
hello hello we have a class and I we can
get the uh it's okay sh
shh thank
you
maximed that actually in this case for
this simple wave equation it's the only
speed all right now of course yes um Can
can you give an example of the Springs
where it's uh least action but not least
but not minimum
energy sorry different you said least
action is different than than minimiz
total energy wait
yeah minimizing the to minimizing the
energy is a thing you do to find the
equilibrium
configuration okay so for example if we
just had a single particle a single
spring just a uh then it would
be uh Q do
SAR over 2
m
um the energy would be plus the lran
minus plus or minus depending on we're
talking about lran or energy uh some
spring constant over 2 * Q ^2 now
minimizing the energy in this case would
correspond to Q do equal 0 and Q equals
z right that would minimize the energy
that corresponds to the equilibrium
configuration of the spring the static
unmoving equilibrium
configuration the principle of Le
action has to do not only with
equilibrium but has to do with any kind
of motion of the system oscillations
back and forth whatever it
does and
um the least
action is determined in terms of the
minus sign least energy in terms of the
plus sign uh we can come back to this
distinction between Lans and energy I
didn't want to do that now I wanted to
show you rather how one goes from a
mechanical system to a uh uh to a field
Theory uh can I go back way back when
you decided how much the stretchiness
was why did it only involve the vertical
not the horizontal distance okay
[Music]
um yeah let's let's go back over that a
little bit
now first of all let's assume this is an
assumption it's an assumption that can
be justified but I don't want to justify
it now let's assume that the springs
that the mass points only move
vertically that they don't have any
horizontal
motion right somewhat arbitrary
assumption I will tell you that it's
much harder to get him moving this way
but but let's assume it for the moment
all right
now
the energy in a
spring is typically proportional to the
square of the separation between the two
Mass points and in this case of course
the separation is two components it has
a vertical and a horizontal component I
presume that's what you were asking
about yeah okay so let's uh let's look
at it the horizontal displacement is
Epsilon and the vertical displacement is
fi what is the distance between this
point and this point well it's the
Square t of 5^2 + Epsilon s
right right but the energy in the spring
is not proportional to the distance but
the square of the
distance the square of the distance is
just 5^ 2 + Epsilon
s right so the energy in the spring is
5^2 + Epsilon s but Epsilon is just a
number each one of the springs is
stretched by amount it's just a number
it's fixed it doesn't depend on five so
when I add up all the potential energies
there are all these contributions which
are the Epsilon squares but they're just
a single overall
number don't they blow up too fast they
do blow up too fast but they're still
just a number a number added into the
energy doesn't uh doesn't affect the
equations of motion the only dependence
of U on fi is this term here okay so we
don't have to worry about the other term
just because it's a constant and can't
affect the motion of the
system that's the reason for writing it
in this
form as just 5^
squar if the energy was the magnitude of
the distance then we'd have to be a
little bit cleverer but in this case
it's the square of the distance and the
square of the distance just has the two
terms additively and when I add them all
up I get a whole bunch of Epsilon
squares but they don't do anything so
for all practical purposes then it's
just 5^
squ all right this is if you like it's
the derivation of a field Theory from a
discrete system in the limit that the
discrete system gets more and more
dense uh let me just very quickly
mention the real Point here was deriving
the equations of motion from an action
principle let's write out the action let
me show you that the action can be
written as an
integral and let's see what the action
is when I say it can be written as an
integral I mean in the limit that
Epsilon is small I'll tell you what
let's take a five minute break before I
do
that and uh come back and then write the
action in a need form
needless to
say I did not mean to
imply that this variable C is the speed
of
light but notice that in this way we did
derive an equation that says
unambiguously that the speed of motion
along the string is
C now does that mean that special
relativity is satisfied for this
string not
really uh special relativity I mean that
every Observer would see the string the
sound waves or the waves in this string
moving with the same velocity they
wouldn't if you were moving past the
string and the string was standing
still uh you would see the waves moving
in One
Direction fast fter than moving in the
other
direction and that's because we're
really not talking about special
relativity here we're just talking about
a collection of ordinary
non-relativistic particles connected by
Springs and there was no
expectation that uh that everybody would
see sound or not sound but waves
vibrating up and down the string with
the same
velocity
so uh
well we'll come back to that however
this is a model for how wave propagation
and field Theory occurs and the derives
out of a classical mechanics anyway
let's uh come to the action and write
the action in a form where was where was
the mass in
in where was the
what it is there something like mass in
any of this is there something like math
or mass mass mass like like like
kilograms yeah yeah yeah there was uh it
was this Epsilon here now I could have
put I could have put um all right let's
uh let's go back let's let's not call
this c s for the moment okay let's just
call it
Kappa but it's not the ordinary spring
constant the ordinary spring constant is
Kappa over Epsilon right and let's call
this Epsilon time mu mu for Mass but mu
is not the mass Epsilon time mu is the
mass okay then we would have gotten the
equation Epsilon not uh yeah um we would
have gotten the equation muf dble
dot coming from this term is equal
to Kappa
I
think
times second derivative of f with
respect to x
squared the epsilons would still cancel
the epsilons were in places that uh that
uh has them disappear out of the final
answer potential doesn't have the mass
but the kinetic term does yeah kinetic
term has the mass potential term has a
spring constant like
Factor all right so then I would just
divide this by
new and I would say that the
velocity of
propagation c squared the square of the
Velocity was Kappa over
mu so I could have left a parameter mu
here and I could have left a parameter
Kappa there now in the way that I worked
it out I set mu equal to 1 and I called
Kappa c^
2 good
incidentally you could always choose to
set mu equal to one here um you could
absorb it into the definition of fi you
could rescale fi so as to eat up the
factor mu here when you did so you
wouldn't uh be able to eat up uh you
wouldn't be able to eat it up out of
this term also so you have your choice
there's various ways you can do this
um let's let's talk
about the lran and the action of the
system in particular I want to go to the
Limit Epsilon goes to
zero in which the mechanical system
becomes a field Theory here's the lran
Let's uh let's get rid of the MU here
and replace Kappa by
c^2 as we had it
originally
okay now this sum
Epsilon let's let's remember the
connection between integrals and sums an
integral DX of anything let's say F
ofx in the limit is equivalent to let's
just put a double arrow there is the
same thing as the
sum of f
ofx over the discrete set of points X of
I let's
say and the DX becomes Epsilon the DX
becomes Delta X and in our case Delta X
is
Epsilon so that's all we have to do is
to replace sums by integrals
and likewise to replace
derivatives or differences by
derivatives not necessarily the same
function but a function DF by DX is of
course a
replacement in the limit
for f ofx + Epsilon - F
ofx /
Epsilon we use that we Ed that when we
uh when we replaced these these things
here by derivatives okay let's go to the
action and see if we can work it out and
find that it's a nice integral of things
that make sense from from calculus point
of view the first term in the action
that's easy Epsilon times the sum of 5
do^ 2 according to this rule it should
just be replaced by the integral
DX 1/2 that 1/2 is the 1/2 that appears
out here the Epsilon goes away because
it's really just
DX Time 5 do^
2 that was easy and painless let me
write it 5 do^ 2 *
DX integrated from where to where well
integrated from the
bridge to the peg so to speak integrated
over the range of
X it's called it from the bridge to the
peg this is right this is the lran but
so far this is just the kinetic term in
lran okay this is the kinetic terminal
agian now for the potential terminal
agian so let's uh
okay the potential termin inal agian
that's
U we want minus U but let me write down
U that's equal
to
summation c^
2 well let's take the c^ S
outside over
two Delta f
i means F of I +
1- - 5
I
squared /
Epsilon all right now I don't have
enough epsilons downstairs here to make
it the derivative of f with respect to X
SAR this looks like it wants to be the
square of the derivative of f but it
doesn't have enough epsilons downstairs
on the other hand it also doesn't have
enough epsilons upstairs to turn it into
an integral you need an Epsilon upstairs
to turn it into an
integral but you need another Epsilon
downstairs to turn this into a square of
a derivative well that's easy just put
an Epsilon in there in the numerator and
another Epsilon down stairs in the
denominator now we have something which
obviously can be turned into an integral
I want to subtract the potential
energy so that's minus
12 the2 is the same2 c^2 over 2- c^2
over
2 Epsilon in the numerator just becomes
DX again let's
integral
DX that's the Epsilon in the numerator
and then each one of these becomes the
each factor here becomes a derivative of
five with respect to X
squared no more Epsilon Epsilon is gone
it smoothly disappeared into the
definition of derivatives and
integrals okay so now I can write down
the action I've written it but or I can
write down the uh the
lran the lran
L is 12 the
integral
of d by dt^
2 that's the first term that's the same
as F dot d by DT ^ 2 minus c^
2 D by dx^
2 and that's it DX all times
X that's the lunian now notice the lran
is an integral now it's not a sum over
terms it's become an
integral if we draw SpaceTime let's draw
SpaceTime
time
space X and in our problem X only varies
between the two ends of the string so
what do we call this again I I keep
forgetting the names of the parts of the
violin the bridge and the uh the bridge
end and the peg end
right all right so space time is all
between the bridge and the
peg of course there will be nothing to
prevent us from imagining an infinite
string but uh let's con let's uh be more
have more realistic violin for the
moment
from the bridge to the peg is where
SpaceTime is and time can go from minus
infinity to Infinity right the fs are
labeled by the points along the
x-axis and the
lran has morphed from a sum
over points and Springs to an integral
over
X all right that's the Lan but what
about the action the action is the
integral of the LR
with respect to time from some initial
to some final time so let's pick an
initial time over here T
initial T
final before we write it let's remember
what we're supposed to do we pick an
initial condition and an initial
condition means we specify The Q's well
what are the q's in our
problem the fs instead of having a
discrete collection of fi we have a fi
at every point along the horizontal axis
so we set up the problem of saying
supposing fi takes on some particular
functional value some particular
function
initially five of X
initially it's called f initial here
and five final
here what is the history of the field
Theory what is the history of the motion
of the spring which interpolates between
them right what's the action the action
is just this lran integrated over time
so let's just write it
action action
notice how symmetrical it's become
between space and
time it has derivatives of f with
respect to time squared now of course in
the setting that we're going to be
interested in C is going to be equal to
the speed of light and as everybody
knows the speed of light is
one so let's uh let's just work in units
in which the speed of sound light uh
violin propagation whatever it is is is
equal to
one that's just a choice of the relation
between time units and space units here
we wouldn't be using light years and
years uh we'd be using uh how far does a
signal travel along a uh violin string
in one second and that sort of thing but
if we chose units in which the speed of
propagation was one then we would have a
marvelously simple
expression for the lran involving F
second derivative of f with respect to T
and second deriva of a f with respect to
X integrated over x and t in other words
integrated over this whole space time
region I note for you the existence of
this minus
sign right now I think we're close to
finishing for the evening I'm getting
tired but I think uh it should be
apparent to you that this minus sign
that's there has something or other to
do with special
relativity it's somehow connected to the
X squares minus t sares which represent
invariant quantities yeah I'm getting
confused between second derivatives this
oh this is not second derivative this is
square of first derivatives oh okay yeah
good all right that's yeah yeah that's
good in the equation of motion second
derivatives
appear in the action in the lran squares
of first derivatives appear now what's
that like that's very very much like
fals Ma and its relationship to kinetic
energy in the lran appears kinetic
energy velocities
squared in the equation of motion
appears acceleration which is qou Dot
okay how did that happen well remember
what you're supposed to do you're
supposed to take the derivative of the
lanan with respect to Q
dot that gives you some Q Dot and then
differentiate it again to get Q double
dot that's in the equation of motion so
in the equation of motion the wave
equation we had second derivative of f
with respect to
t^2 minus second derivative of f with
respect to x^2 equals z that was
equation of motion but in the lran
itself you don't have second derivatives
you have squares of first derivatives
which is like the kinetic energy of a
particle
okay so lran as a rule has first
derivatives squared the equation of
motion that follows from it has second
derivatives that's a good question thank
you yes
sir we started out this model with the
contic energy equal to 12
MV which is not the relativistic energy
no no no no no no no we're not doing
relativity at the moment this is just a
uh we're doing
uh yeah that was something and we start
making relistic conclusions at the end
well not really not really we just have
we don't this has nothing to do with
speed of light it has nothing to do with
special relativity it's just a wave
moving up and down the x-axis now I
point out to you that if we substituted
the speed of light and set the speed of
light equal to one we're starting to see
a
pattern right but remember that pattern
is going to be about Fields not about
the motion of
particles so while it's true the kinetic
energy of a particle in relativity does
not have the form of 1 12 mv^ 2 the
kinetic energy of a field does have the
form of the square of a not a velocity
in space but a velocity and field space
in other words in our model the FI
Direction was really we really imagining
that it was a spatial Direction but now
abstract from that just drop the the
whole framework that we started with
where fi was actually a motion along a
certain axis and now now just think
about it as a field in
space now there's nothing that anybody
says that would tell us that a field
cannot have a kinetic energy which is
the square of its time
derivative it's not the motion of a
particle in space it's the motion of a
field in field
space
yeah
okay look like we're going to go home a
little bit early but uh if there are no
questions I'm happy to stay around for a
few more minutes for questions you need
to integrate over time also the action
integrates you integrate over time you
need
another you just want to
use doual sign
all right now
convention the fact that there's two
integrals is indicated fully by the fact
that there's a DX and a DT there and
there's no need to specify that one
right so it's standard convention is an
integral means uh integral over any
number of dimensions and it's this thing
which tells you how many dimensions are
there it's really a path integral right
no it's not a pan integral the action
it's it's a volume in in space a volume
integral It's A Spacetime volume
integral it's not an integral along a
path in space well the the action would
be no it oh not this action no the
action of a particle would be a path
integral not a path integral in the
sense of findan but an integral along a
line a line integral yeah if you had
infinite distance between your bridge
and Peg then you essentially have one
set of one fixed curve going this way at
velocity C on your diagram space time
diagram and then one going the other
way well we haven't discussed the nature
of the solutions of this equation yet
let's come to that next time but if you
didn't have a peg in a in a b whatever B
is if forget then we would just take
these out to infinity and uh there would
be no uh no restriction on the integral
okay that was good I enjoyed that thank
[Music]
you the proceeding program is
copyrighted by Stanford University
please visit us at stanford.edu